{
    "id": "ae668aeaa551474194c02d7e27747877",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I was taken ............................. when they told me that I had failed.",
            "description": "To be taken aback is to be shocked.",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "over",
                "aback"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She takes ............................ her mother.",
            "description": "To take after somebody is to resemble them.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "off",
                "after"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "My brother tried to take ............................... my toys but I didn't let him.",
            "description": "To take something away is to remove it from somebody.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "away",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The minister refused to take ………………….. his remarks.",
            "description": "To take your remarks back is to retract them.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "back",
                "down"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The court ordered the company to take ………………………. their hoardings.",
            "description": "To take something down is to remove it. ",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "in",
                "down"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I took him ………………………. a foreigner.",
            "description": "Take for means regard as.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "for",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A kind woman took …………………….. the pup that was abandoned by its masters.",
            "description": "To take someone in is to give home to them.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "out",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Please take ……………………….. your shoes before entering the temple.",
            "description": "To take off shoes is to remove them.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "off",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The plane took ……………………… at the scheduled time.",
            "description": "When a plane takes off, it begins to fly.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "off",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t want to take …………………….. any more work at the moment.",
            "description": "To take on work is to agree to do it.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on",
                "out"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The company is planning to take …………………………… more programmers.",
            "description": "To take on people is to hire them. ",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A multinational firm is going to take ………………………… our company.",
            "description": "To take over a company is to gain control of it.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "off",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}